<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>It is humbly offered by some uninterested persons that the laying a greater duty on low-wines, or spirits drawn from melasses than on other spirits, or the total prohibition thereof (which will certainly be the effect) will be of a bad consequence to the nation for the following reasons</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09306</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">62369335</idno>
  <idno type="VID">187959</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248532650</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing I1083A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC N9669</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">62369335</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09306)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 187959)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2850:22)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>It is humbly offered by some uninterested persons that the laying a greater duty on low-wines, or spirits drawn from melasses than on other spirits, or the total prohibition thereof (which will certainly be the effect) will be of a bad consequence to the nation for the following reasons</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1690]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Sutro Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Distilling industries --  Law and legislation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Alcoholic beverages --  Law and legislation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1689-1702 --  Sources.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:187959:1"/>
            <head>It is Humbly Offered, by some <hi>Uninterested Persons,</hi> That the laying a greater Duty on <hi>Low-Wines,</hi> or <hi>Spirits</hi> drawn from <hi>Melasses</hi> than on other <hi>Spirits,</hi> or the total Prohibition thereof (which will certainly be the Effect) will be of a bad Consequence to the Nation, for the following Reasons.</head>
            <p n="1">I. BRANDY or <hi>Fine Spirits</hi> being only to be drawn from the Fruit of the Vine or the Sugar-Cane, <hi>viz. Sugar</hi> or <hi>Melasses;</hi> the former being Discouraged by the Prohibition of all <hi>Foreign-Brandy,</hi> the latter ought to be Incouraged, because nothing else will make <hi>Brandy</hi> that will Equalize that of <hi>France.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="2">II. As to <hi>Wine</hi> and <hi>Fruit</hi> that is Imported, it is a very small Quantity that is Distilled; for no Man designedly brings in that which is bad: where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Prohibiting the Distilling thereof, will be of great Loss to the Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chant: For at this present, there's some Quantity here which is not worth Freight and Customs; and will be less worth if Distilling is forbid.</p>
            <p n="3">III. Therefore, In case a larger Duty is design'd to be laid on <hi>Fine Spirits</hi> drawn from <hi>Melasses, &amp;c.</hi> than <hi>Foul Spirits</hi> drawn from <hi>Corn;</hi> The Only Easy and Advantageous Way is, by an <hi>Additional-Duty</hi> on all <hi>Melasses</hi> to be paid at the <hi>Custom-House,</hi> which will absolutely prevent any Disputes which may be between the <hi>Excise-Officers</hi> and the <hi>Distillers</hi> about the Quality of the <hi>Spirits,</hi> and will Save to the King about 20000 <hi>l. per Annum,</hi> which will be drawn back from the Customs on Unpurged <hi>Sugars</hi> Exported: For if <hi>Melasses</hi> be so Burthened that it cannot be Distilled here, the <hi>Refiners</hi> and <hi>Distillers</hi> Trade must fall; and consequently Unpurged <hi>Sugars</hi> must be Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported to be Worked abroad.</p>
            <p n="4">IV. If therefore we intend totally to prevent the Importation of <hi>French</hi> or <hi>Foreign Brandy,</hi> we must Encourage the Manufactury of that of equal Goodness here; which will be a great Advantage to the Nation, by Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploying our own People, and will keep our Money in the Nation; which hath been, and may be sent to <hi>France</hi> for Purchasing the Growth of that Kingdom.</p>
            <p n="5">V. The Discouraging the <hi>Refiners</hi> and <hi>Distillers</hi> Trade here, will be of a very bad Consequence to our <hi>Plantations</hi> (whose Burthen already is very great) and Encourage the <hi>Plantations</hi> of our Neighbours: For they are at liberty to give us what they please for our Unpurged <hi>Sugars,</hi> if we cannot Work them here; and so will consequently lessen our Shipping that are usu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally Employed to our <hi>Islands.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="6">VI. This Discouraging of our <hi>Plantations</hi> will have a great Influence on <hi>Ireland,</hi> from whence they are Annually Supplied with Beef, Pork, and all sorts of Provisions in great Quantities; and also may be some Prejudice to the <hi>Guiny-Trade.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>